Hermann Hagedorn Papers
Hermann Hagedorn Papers
1904-1962
Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964
2.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, novelist, biographer. Correspondence (1905-1962), with George Pierce Baker, Lucien Price, Alice Ehlers, Albert Schweitzer, Van Wyck Brooks, Reinhold Niebuhr, Jack London, and others; research files on subjects of his biographies: Edwin Arlington Robinson, Theodore Roosevelt, and Schweitzer; manuscripts of writings (1904-1958); and memorabilia (1907-1962), including clippings and photographs.
146331
Biographical History
Hermann Hagedorn, biographer of Theodore Roosevelt, poet, and novelist, was born in New York on 18 July 1882, the son of Hermann and Anna (Schwedler) Hagedorn. He prepared at the Hill School and took his bachelor's degree in 1907 at Harvard College. He married Dorothy Oakley in 1908. After traveling in Europe and studying at the University of Berlin and Columbia, he returned to Harvard in the spring of 1909 as an instructor in English and an assistant in comparative literature to Barrett Wendell. He taught there for two years. Novels, plays, and volumes of verse followed. He wrote lyrics for the Peterborough pageant and was affiliated with the artists' colony in Peterborough, N.H., as a director of the Edward MacDowell Association. With Porter Emerson Browne, Julian Street, and Charles Hanson Towne he founded the Vigilantes, an organization of American writers founded in 1916 to support American citizenship and preparedness for the war.
During the pre-convention campaign of 1916 he met Theodore Roosevelt, whose personality captivated him; the resulting friendship shaped the course of his career. The former president cooperated with him in the writing of The Boys' Life of Theodore Roosevelt, published in 1918. After Roosevelt's death the following year, Hermann Hagedorn became assistant secretary and later executive secretary of the Roosevelt Memorial Association, an affiliation he maintained for the rest of his life. From the association's offices in the Roosevelt birthplace site in New York City, he researched other books on the former president: Roosevelt in the Badlands, Roosevelt, Prophet of Unity, The Bugle that Woke America, and The Roosevelt Family of Sagamore Hill. He also edited several selections of the president's writings, including the twenty-volume Works of Theodore Roosevelt. Leonard Wood, the military surgeon who was a Roosevelt confidant, and Edwin Arlington Robinson, the poet whose popularity Roosevelt encouraged, were subjects of his biographies. He was the director of the Theodore Roosevelt Centennial Commission from 1955 to 1959.
Other subjects of his biographical pen were William Boyce Thompson, the mining operator, Robert S. Brookings, merchant, philanthropist, and founder of the Brookings Institution, and Albert Schweitzer. A collection of biographical sketches, Americans: A Book of Lives, was published in 1946. His books for children, widely used in schools, include Book of Courage and We, the People. Two later works in verse are Combat at Midnight (1940) and The Bomb that Fell on America (1946); letters regarding the publication and public reception of the latter title make up a part of the correspondence in these papers. In The Hyphenated Family; An American Saga, he tells the story of his German-American family. During much of his adult life he lived in Santa Barbara, Calif., where he died on 27 July 1964.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Hermann Hagedorn Papers comprise Correspondence of scattered dates, Memorabilia, partial Research files on three subjects of his biographies, manuscripts of some 130 stories and other writings, and a small Biographical file. Although most dated items predate 1950, the span dates of the papers are 1904-1962. Most of the manuscripts carry no dates.
Correspondence--incoming letters and carbons of his replies chronologically arranged--dates from 1905 to 1962. There are 375 letters addressed to Hermann Hagedorn, 102 of his letters, and 33 letters addressed to other correspondents. The earliest letters are from friends and teachers during his undergraduate days at Harvard: George Pierce Baker, LeBaron Russell Briggs, Mark A. DeWolfe Howe, Bliss Perry, Lucien Price, and Barrett Wendell. Edwin Arlington Robinson is the subject of some correspondence from 1935 and 1936. Letters of March 1936 were generated by a memorandum on how best to allocate a half-million-dollar fund given to the American Institute of Arts and Letters; memoranda concerning the endowment fund are located with memorabilia in box 1.
The heaviest concentration of letters is from the 1940s. Albert Schweitzer is the subject of many letters from 1944 to 1946, when the author was preparing his biography. Correspondents include Julius Seelye Bixler, Alice Ehlers, Edith G. H. Lenel, Emmy Martin, Hubert W. Peet, and Everett Skillings, as well as Albert and Hélène Schweitzer themselves. There are carbons of Hermann Hagedorn's letters to Albert Schweitzer, but there are no original letters from Albert Schweitzer in these papers. Copies of Albert Schweitzer's letters to Hermann Hagedorn are located in the research files in boxes 2 and 3. Also in the same files are copies and extracts of Albert Schweitzer letters to other correspondents.
Other correspondents include Van Wyck Brooks, Jack London, Lewis Mumford, Reinhold Niebuhr, and Paul Tillich. A complete index of the correspondence is appended to this inventory. From 1946 there are letters, some of them addressed to the Pacific Coast Publishing Company, that relate to the publication and public reception of Hermann Hagedorn's book The Bomb that Fell on America. Some other correspondence appears elsewhere in these papers. In box 2 there is a small file of correspondence, 1944-1946, exchanged between Hermann Hagedorn and the Reference Department of the Library of Congress, on the subject of books about Albert Schweitzer; these letters are not indexed in the index of correspondents.
Memorabilia from 1907 to 1962 is arranged in boxes 1 and 2. There are clippings of articles by Hermann Hagedorn, including tear sheets of his contributions to The Outlook, clippings about him, photographs, promotional files (of readers' comments, blurb copy, and the like) on four of his books, published reviews of his books, and other items. One folder holds memoranda and other material relating to the use of an American Institute of Arts and Letters endowment fund.
Research files on three subjects of Hermann Hagedorn's biographies are arranged in boxes 2 and 3. Although not complete, these files do hold clippings, notes, and other material used by the author. Edwin Arlington Robinson is represented by clippings, Hagedorn's notes, and other items. Two small folders of printed material on Theodore Roosevelt are followdd by a more extensive file on Albert Schweitzer, part of the notes on which Hagedorn based his biography. There are folders with copies of 22 Albert Schweitzer letters (no originals), 1920-1945, copies of a letter from Hélène Schweitzer and excerpts from additional Albert Schweitzer letters, clippings about Albert Schweitzer, and notes. Typescript memoirs of Albert Schweitzer by Hubert W. Peet and Maude Royden are present, as is a translation from the Swedish of a memoir by Schweitzer himself in which he describes his visit to Uppsala in 1920. Four folders of photographs include 31 snapshots and other prints mailed by Schweitzer to Hagedorn in 1945; a caption list in Albert Schweitzer's handwriting is separately foldered. One of the photographs listed there, number 10, reproduced as the frontispiece of Prophet in the Wilderness, is not now located. Further details on holdings appear in the accompanying shelflist.
Manuscripts of Hermann Hagedorn's writings, 1904 to 1958 with many undated pieces, are arranged in boxes 3 and 4. The 130-odd manuscripts include approximately 30 stories and approximately 60 poems. There are no complete manuscripts of his books, but there is one chapter of Prophet in the Wilderness, apparently not part of the book as published. The earliest item is a 27-page dramatic poem in German, "Das mitternächtliche Königsreich," in a bound leather notebook. A section of miscellaneous manuscripts ends with several unidentified items. A detailed listing of the manuscripts is part of the shelflist.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Biography; Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Ehlers, Alice.; Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964.; London, Jack, 1876-1916.; Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1892-1971.; Price, Lucien, 1883-1964.; Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Biography, Authorship.; Poets, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs.; Poems.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Poets.; Biographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Hermann Hagedorn, 1964.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material, ca. 1922; undated; holo. and ts (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1905 (Box 1)
  - 1906-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1912-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1944 Sep-Oct (Box 1)
  - 1944 Nov-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1945 Jan-Apr (Box 1)
  - 1945 May (Box 1)
  - 1945 Jun (Box 1)
  - 1945 Jul-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1946 Jan-Feb (Box 1)
  - 1946 Mar 1 - 19 (Box 1)
  - 1946 Mar 20-31 (Box 1)
  - 1946 Apr 1 -15 (Box 1)
  - 1946 Apr 16-30 (Box 1)
  - 1946 May (Box 1)
  - 1946 Jun (Box 1)
  - 1946 Jul-Dec (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1962 (Box 1)
  - undated (Box 1)
  - n.y. (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - American Institute of Arts and Letters endowment, March 1936; memoranda, covering letter, and mailing list, holo. and ts (Box 1)
  - Clippings about Hermann Hagedorn, 1936-1958; undated; pr. mat. (Box 1)
  - Clippings of articles by Hermann Hagedorn, 1957; undated; pr. mat. (Box 1)
  - Clippings of work by Hermann Hagedorn in The Outlook, 1923-1925; pr. mat. (Box 1)
  - Clippings of other published work by Hermann Hagedorn, 1907-1936; pr. mat. (Box 1)
  - Photographs (11) of Hermann Hagedorn, undated (Box 1)
  - Promotional file on The Bomb that Fell on America, ca. 1946 (Box 2)
  - Promotional file on The Hyphenated Family, ca. 1960 (Box 2)
  - Promotional file on Prophet in the Wilderness, ca. 1947 (Box 2)
  - Promotional file on While There is Time, ca. 1962 (Box 2)
  - Reminiscences of Hermann Hagedorn by Harold T. Pulsifer, undated; ts, 4 pp. (Box 2)
  - Reviews of books by Hermann Hagedorn, pr. mat. (Box 2)
  - The Hyphenated Family, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Menschenfreund im Urwald (Prophet in the Wilderness), 1955; clippings from German publications (Box 2)
  - Prophet in the Wilderness, 1947-1949; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Other works, 1945-1958 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1936-1949; undated (Box 2)
- Research files
  - Edwin Arlington Robinson
    - Address by Kenneth C. M. Sills, 12 May 1935; presented at the memorial meeting in honor of Edwin Arlington Robinson, Gardiner, Maine, ts, 8 pp. (2 copies) (Box 2)
    - Bibliographic notes, undated (Box 2)
    - Clippings, 1920-1936; pr. mat. (Box 2)
    - Clippings mounted on scrapbook pages, 1905-1931 (Box 2)
    - Notes, holo. and ts, undated (Box 2)
  - Theodore Roosevelt
    - Printed items from the Roosevelt Centennial, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous items, various dates; pr. mat. (Box 2)
  - Albert Schweitzer (Box 2)
    - Correspondence between Hermann Hagedorn and the Reference Department of the Library of Congress, 1944-1946; Not indexed in the index of correspondence that is appended to this inventory. (Box 2)
    - Clippings and articles about Albert Schweitzer, pr. mat.
      - 1910-1935 (Box 2)
      - 1938-1950 (Box 2)
      - 1951-1954, undated (Box 2)
    - Clippings and articles about Albert Schweitzer, 1925-1949; undated; all photostats (Box 2)
    - Envelope that contained letters now at Syracuse and list of notable correspondents, in the handwriting of Hermann Hagedorn, probably 1964 (Box 2)
    - Letters from Albert Schweitzer to Hermann Hagedorn, 1944-1945; 5, all copies, holo. and ts, no originals (Box 2)
    - Letter from Albert Schweitzer to Edith Lenel, dated at Lambaréné, 9 May 1931; 1 copy, in the handwriting of Edith Lenel (Box 3)
    - Letters from Albert Schweitzer to Edith Lenel, dated at various places, 1920-1936; 13, all photostat copies, no originals (Box 3)
    - Letters from Albert Schweitzer to Everett Skillings, dated at Lambaréné, 1943-1944; 3, all typescript copies (Box 3)
    - Letter from Hélène Schweitzer to Everett Skillings, 30 April 1944; typescript copy (Box 3)
    - Letter excerpts from Albert Schweitzer to Alice Ehlers, 2 pp. The letters from which these excerpts are taken date, 1932-1938; typescript copies (Box 3)
    - Memoir by H. W. Peet, "Where a great man grew up; a visit to Dr. Schweitzer's village in Alsace", undated; undated; 2 copies, ts, 5 pp. and tsc, 12 pp. (Box 3)
    - Memoir by Maude Royden, "Dr. Albert Schweitzer", undated; ts, 15 pp. (Box 3)
    - Memoir by Albert Schweitzer, "A benefactor to the natives of Ogowes primeval forest", undated; undated; translated from the Swedish by Schurer O. Werner; 2 copies; anno. ts, 7 pp. and tsc, 14 pp. (Box 3)
    - Notes, holo., undated (Box 3)
    - Notes, ts, undated (Box 3)
    - Photographs
      - Lists of photographs, undated; 2 items, one in the hand of Albert Schweitzer, another in that of Edith Lenel (Box 3)
      - Photograph of a sculpture portrait of Albert Schweitzer, May 1949; Inscribed by the sculptor, Louis Mayer, to Hermann Hagedorn (Box 3)
      - Photographic prints of Albert Schweitzer (14), including some negative prints (Box 3)
      - Snapshots and other prints, labeled by Schweitzer and mailed from Gunsbach to Hermann Hagedorn, 1945; 31 of the 32 listed by Schweitzer (Box 3)
    - Queries submitted to Albert Schweitzer by Hermann Hagedorn, 1944 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous items, mostly pr. mat., various dates (Box 3)
- Writings
  - Books
    - Americans: A Book of Lives, chapter on George Washington Carver, holo., 14 pp. (Box 3)
    - The Hyphenated Family
      - Draft A, rev. holo., incomplete (Box 3)
      - Draft B, anno. tsc
        - Chapter 1 (Box 3)
        - Chapter 2 (Box 3)
        - Chapter 3 (Box 3)
        - Chapter 7 (Box 3)
        - Fragments (Box 3)
      - Draft C, Chapter 3, tsc (Box 3)
      - Draft D, anno. tsc, incomplete (Box 3)
    - Prophet in the Wilderness
      - Chapter 15, not part of the book as published? (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Box 3)
  - Dramatic poem, "Das mitternächtliche Königreich", 25 August 1904; holo., 27 pp. in a bound leather notebook (Box 3)
  - Speeches
    - Remarks at an awards presentation of the Theodore Roosevelt Association, undated; tsc, 10 pp. (Box 3)
    - "A Sanctuary of the Free Spirit", 4 July 1958; remarks by Hermann Hagedorn at the dedication of Theodore Roosevelt Island, (2 copies), anno. tsc draft, 4 pp. and mimeographed copy, 4 pp. (Box 3)
  - Stories
    - The Angel of the Resurrection, undated; tsc, 5 pp. (Box 3)
    - The Blue Eyed Johnny, undated; tsc, 35 pp. (Box 3)
    - The Byronic Mechanic, undated; tsc, 5 pp. (Box 3)
    - The Daughter of the Confederacy, undated; ts, 5 pp. (Box 3)
    - The Engineers, undated; ts, 2 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Growth of Tough Luck Zoggie, undated; anno, ts, 33 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Growth of Tough Luck Zoggie, undated; holo., approx. 73 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Heavenward Journey of Old Doc John, undated; anno. ts, 15 pp. (Box 4)
    - It Is the Hour of Stars, undated; anno. ts, 11 pp.; See also There Is Always the Star (Box 4)
    - A Leader in Civic Movements, undated; tsc, 7 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Mirage, undated; ts, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - A Mother Explains the Younger Generation, undated; ts, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - My Friend Jack, undated; anno. ts, 10 pp. (Box 4)
    - My Mormon, undated; anno. ts, 7 pp. (Box 4)
    - Pete Halliday's Housekeeper, undated; tsc, 9 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Politics of Politics, undated; tsc, 5 pp. (Box 4)
    - Prohibition's Farce, undated; tsc, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - Remembered Springtime, undated; ts, 9 pp. (Box 4)
    - The State Fair, undated; tsc, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - A Strike for Manna Dew, undated; anno. ts, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Talker, undated; ts, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - There Is a Gleam in Amarillo's Eyes, undated; anno. ts, 8 pp. (Box 4)
    - There Is Always the Star, undated; anno. ts, 10 pp. (Box 4)
    - There Is Always the Star, undated; rev. holo., 10 pp. (Box 4)
    - This Fellow Is on Fire!, undated; rev. holo., 19 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Vicissitudes of a Landlubber, undated; ts, 17 pp. (Box 4)
    - Vision!, undated; anno. tsc, 9 pp. (Box 4)
    - Why, Asked the Boy, undated; holo., 2 pp. (Box 4)
  - Verse
    - Affirmation, undated; rev. holo., 1 p. (Box 4)
    - America, 1939; undated; holo., 1 p. (Box 4)
    - Das Antlitz der Medusa (The Face of the Medusa), undated; ts, 10 pp., a translation into German, possibly by Ruby Marie Simon (Box 4)
    - Die Bombe, die auf Amerika fiel, undated; anno. ts, 50 pp., translation by Ruby Marie Simon (Box 4)
    - Die Bombe, die auf Amerika fiel, Teil I, undated; tsc, 17 pp. (Box 4)
    - Die Bombe, die auf Amerika fiel, Teil III, undated; anno. ts, 10 pp. (Box 4)
    - Broadway and Forty-Second, undated; rev. holo., 1 p. (Box 4)
    - Combat at Midnight, undated; 6 poems from; ts, 18 pp., translated into German by Ruby Marie Simon (Box 4)
    - Combat at Midnight, undated; ts, 23 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Crusaders, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - East and West, undated; holo., 2 pp. (Box 4)
    - Faces, undated; holo., 2 pp. (Box 4)
    - God Is Not Mocked, undated; 2 copies; holo., 2 pp. and 1 p. (Box 4)
    - Lights, undated; undated; holo., 1 p., and anno. ts, 1 p. (Box 4)
    - The News from Quidnet, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - Not by Themselves, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - So This Is Marriage!, 8 May 1928; To Edith A. and Adolf G. Hagedorn), ts, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - Starry Night, undated; rev, holo., 1 p. (Box 4)
    - There Is a Need of Bonfires, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - What's Right with America?, undated; holo., 2 pp. (Box 4)
    - While There Is Time, undated; holo., 8 pp. (Box 4)
    - While There Is Time, undated; ts, 8 pp. (Box 4)
    - While There Is Time, undated; pr. mat., pre-publication printing (Box 4)
    - The Wrestlers, undated; rev, holo., 19 pp. (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous poems, individual poem titles are listed on the front of the two folders
      - 13 poems, undated; holo., ts, tsc, and pr. mat. (Box 4)
      - 18 poems (some in duplicate), mostly from the collection Combat at Midnight, undated; ts and tsc, some annotated (Box 4)
      - Fragments (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous writings
    - American Citizenship, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Anti-Nicotine Reformer, undated; ts, 2 pp. (Box 4)
    - Appeal for funds on Albert Schweitzer's 70th Birthday, ca. 1945; anno. ts, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Boyce Thompson Institute of Plant Research, undated; holo., 11 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Breakfast Station, undated; ts, 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - Frank Laubach, undated; a biographical sketch; anno. ts, 25 pp. (Box 4)
    - Frank Linderman as I Knew Him, 1939; holo., 7 pp. (Box 4)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt, undated; tsc, 13 pp. (Box 4)
    - Frontier, undated; outline for a play in one act; anno. ts, 8 pp. (Box 4)
    - George Washington Carver, undated; tsc, 14 pp. (Box 4)
    - The Golden Calf, undated; tsc, 5 pp. (Box 4)
    - Industrial Histories, undated; 6 copies; each is tsc, 6 pp. (Box 4)
    - Law in Tennessee, undated; ts, 1 p. (Box 4)
    - November Dawn, undated; ts, 1 p. (Box 4)
    - Oklahoma, undated; ts, 1 p. (Box 4)
    - On Religion, undated; holo., 7 pp. (Box 4)
    - Tribute to Josephine Preston Peabody, undated; tsc, 1 p. (Box 4)
    - Unidentified, undated; holo., 3 pp. (Box 4)
    - Unidentified fragment of a play, undated; pp. 19-41, anno. ts (Box 4)
Index to correspondence
Abbreviations used: ALS = autograph (handwritten) letter, signed; TLS = typescript letter, signed.
Adams, James Truslow 1936 Jul 22 Southport, Ct. (TLS)
Allen, Henry J. 1946 Apr 2 Wichita, Kan. (TLS)
Austin, Mary no year Aug 16 p.p. (ALS)
Avitt, Louise 1946 Apr 17 Los Angeles (postcard)
Babson, Roger W. 1946 Mar 20 Babson Park, Ma. (secretarial) 1946 May 5 New York (ALS)
Bailard, Edna B. 1946 Apr? Carpinteria, Calif. (ALS)
Bailey, Arthur Ward 1946 Jul 9 Los Altos, Calif. Pacific Coast Publishing Co. (TLS)
Baker, George Pierce 1905 Nov 21 Cambridge (ALS) 1905 Nov 29 Cambridge (TLS)
Baker & Taylor Co. 1946 Jun 7 New York (telegram)
Baldwin, Hanson W. 1946 Mar 19 New York (TLS)
Barrows, David Prescott 1946 Mar 19 Berkeley, Calif. (TLS)
Bartlett, Truman H. 1913 Oct 11 Chocorva, N.H. (ALS)
Baylor, Anna Manning 1946 Aug 11 South Byfield, Mass. (ALS)
Beach, Goodwin B. 1946 Apr 6 Hartford, Ct. (ALS)
Belden, Albert D. 1946 Jun 17 Los Angeles (ALS)
Bell, Bernard Iddings 1946 Mar 19 Chicago (ALS) 1946 Apr 7 Chicago (ALS) 1946 Apr? Chicago (ALS)
Bell, Laird 1946 Jun 19 Chicago (TLS)
Bergel, Kurt 1944 Nov 2 Deep Springs, Calif. (TLS)
Beston, Henry 1946 Mar 16 Nobleboro, Me. (ALS)
Bixler, J.S. 1944 Dec 18 Waterville, Me. (TLS)
Boas, Franz 1905 Dec 19 New York (TLS)
Boddy, Manchester 1946 Mar 15 n.p. (TLS)
Bonnell, John Sutherland 1946 Mar 19 New York (TLS)
Bonner, Amy 1946 May 25 Chicago Pacific Coast Publishing Co. (TLS)
Boyd, William R., Jr. 1947 Sep 12 New York (TLS)
Bridges, Robert 1936 May 4 New York (TLS)
Briggs, Ina C. 1946 May 14 New York (TLS, to Mrs. Walter S. Lemmon)
Briggs, LeBaron Russell 1905 Sep 13 Plymouth, Mass. (ALS)
Brookings, Isabel 1936 Jul 2 Gloucester, Mass. (ALS) 1936 Jul 7 Gloucester, Mass. (ALS) 1936 Jul 8 Gloucester, Mass. (ALS)
Brooks, Van Wyck 1936 Mar 5 Summerville, S.C. (ALS) 1936 Mar 13 Summerville, S.C. (ALS) 1936 Jun 8 Westport, Ct. (ALS) 1936 Jul 21 Westport, Ct. (postcard) no date Westport, Ct. (ALS) 1946 Feb 18 Carmel, Calif. (ALS) 1946 Feb 23 Carmel, Calif. (ALS)
Buck, Pearl S. 1945 Jul 2 Perkasie, Pa. (TLS) 1945 Jul 5 New York (TLS)
Bynner, Witter 1905 Nov 1 New York (TLS)
Canaday, 1946 Mar 15 Toledo, Ohio (Secretarial)
Cartier, Elma Rumsey 1946 --- -- New York (ALS)
Chambrun, Jacques 1946 May 27 New York (TLS) 1946 Jun 3 New York (telegram)
Charnwood, Dorothea Mary Roby (Thorpe) 1931 Aug 12 London (ALS)
Charnwood, Godfrey Rathbone Benson 1931 Aug 11 London (ALS)
Claxton, Allen E. 1946 Apr 1 New York (TLS)
Clinton, Clifford E. 1946 Jun 25 Hollywood, Calif. (TLS)
Combe, Andrew 1946 Mar 31 Ft. Leavenworth, Kan (ALS)
Compton, Arthur H. 1946 May 15 St. Louis (TLS)
Conant, James B. 1946 Apr 15 Cambridge (TLS)
Conried, Heinrich 1905 Nov 20 New York (to Kuno Francke) (TLS) 1905 Dec 15 New York (TLS)
Constable, Wilna L. 1946 Apr 23 Orlando, Flor. (ALS)
Conway, Rose A. See Harry S. Truman
Cushing, Harvey 1931 Nov 20 Boston (TLS)
Damrosch, Walter 1936 Mar 3 [New York] (TLS)
Davenport, F.M. 1946 Mar 21 Washington (TLS)
Davenport, Russell 1946 Jun 10 New Haven, Conn. (TLS)
David, Donald K. 1947 Oct 20 Boston (TLS)
Davison, Archibald 1944 Oct 23 Cambridge (TLS)
Desmond, Thomas C. 1962 Apr 17 Newburgh, N.Y. (TLS)
Deutsch, Monroe E. 1946 Apr 5 Berkeley, Calif. (TLS)
Ditzler, Harold E. 1946 Mar 16 Los Angeles (TLS)
Donegan, Horace W.B. 1946 Apr 27 New York (TLS)
Dreier, Mary Elisabeth 1946 Apr 4 Brooksville, Flor. (ALS)
Dulles, John Foster 1946 Mar 15 New York (TLS)
Edwards, Deane 1946 Mar 20 New York (TLS)
Ehlers, Alice 1944 Oct 19 Palos Verdes, Calif. (ALS)
Eichelberger, Clark M. 1946 Apr 10 New York (TLS)